PAUL ADAMS

Technology Leader

9 406 Stafford Close, Franklin, TN 37069-4360

SUMMARY

Results-oriented, goal-driven technologist with 18+ years of leadership experience in software development and IT infrastructure. Diverse background includes building and motivating teams, strategic planning, SaaS products, private equity-backed startups, growth-stage companies, various technology stacks, and consulting. Strong collaboration, analytical, and communication skills.

EXPERIENCE

Mobile Development Manager

06/2022 - Present

Ceridian

 Leads a team of 10 Android and iOS Engineers who add new features to Dayforce Wallet, a finance app that provides employees on-demand access to their earned wages

Mobile Development Manager

09/2019 - 06/2022

Quore

(2 years, 9 months)

- Led a team of Android and iOS Developers who provided hotel industry software solutions for 85.9K monthly active users
- Employed best practices that assured a 99.9% crash-free architecture and adherence to multiple data privacy regulations
- Promoted personal skill improvement to boost team productivity while ensuring high product quality

Senior Mobile Developer

06/2015 - 09/2019

Contractor

(4 years, 3 months)

- Collaborated with stakeholders and cross-functional teams to devise achievable technology roadmaps for 17 n-tier product initiatives
- · Applied agile software development practices throughout the life-cycle of each project, assuring consistently on-time deliverables
- · Engineered 214 titles among 14 App Store categories
- $\cdot\,$ Designed, developed, and maintained three nonprofit websites

Information Technology Manager

U.S. Army

(16 years, 2 months)

- · Coordinated and supervised the employment, operation, management, and maintenance of information technology systems worldwide in mobile and fixed facilities
- \cdot Wrote programs to handle the collection, manipulation, and distribution of data for an array of applications and requirements
- Operated telecommunications systems, including automated networks and a full spectrum of data links and circuits

PROJECTS

Mobile App Portfolio

https://adams.io/portfolio.pdf

SKILLS

Agile Leadership · Project Budgets ·
Analytics · Technical Writing · Swift ·
Objective-C · Kotlin · Java · Ruby ·
JavaScript · REST · GraphQL ·
PostgreSQL · SQLite · AWS · Azure ·
Firebase · CI/CD · TDD · UI/UX ·
Biometrics · Machine Learning ·
Bluetooth LE · Offshore Resourcing ·
Data Privacy · eAccessibility

COURSES

iOS Development Course
Devmountain, Immersive Cohort 4

IT Specialist Advanced Leader Course

U.S. Army, Honor Graduate

Ranger School U.S. Army

EDUCATION

Graduate Study, Counseling Thomas University

Bachelor's Degree, Psychology Thomas University